C. D. Russell Cartoons
C. D. Russell Cartoons
1921-1964
1948-1954
Russell, C. D. (Clarence D.), 1895-1963.
9 linear ft.
American cartoonist and illustrator, best known for his Pete the Tramp strip. Collection consists of clippings and proofs of cartoons by Russell, proofs from other cartoonists and a few pieces of original art.
3181570
Biographical History
Clarence D. Russell (1895-1963) was an American cartoonist and illustrator, best known for his syndicated comic strip Pete the Tramp. Born in Buffalo, New York, he studied at the Chicago Art Institute and worked as sports editor for Leatherneck Magazine in addition to doing freelance work. During World War I he joined the American Expeditionary Force. After his military service he returned to New York City where he worked for the New York Evening Post and the New York Evening Mail, and contributed to the humorous publication Judge. His sketches of homeless men in Bryant Park led to the creation of Pete the Tramp, which was picked up by King Features Syndicate and ran for more than thirty years.
[Adapted from information found in Famous Artists and Writers, published by King Features Syndicate in 1949 and available online at http://lileks.com/comics/kingfeatures/.]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The C. D. Russell Cartoons (1921-1964) consists of artwork, newspaper clippings, proofs of comic strips by Russell and proofs and clippings of comic strips from other cartoonists.
Original artwork contains two original daily strips, including a 1937 Mickey Mouse cartoon signed by Walt Disney and a 1936 Thimble Theatre cartoon starring Popeye by E.C. Segar. The series also contains undated sketches, including magazine cover designs featuring Ozark Ike.
Printed material (1945-1949) primarily consists of Sunday News, New York's Picture Newspaper issues. The July 4 1948 issue contains color images of First Lady dresses from 1789 to 1945. Documents from the New York Historical Society were found with the cartoon Dick's Adventures in Dreamland.
Works by C.D. Russell (1932-1963) includes mostly color proofs of Pete the Tramp and other topper cartoons, including Bumps, Pete's Pup, Snorky, The Topper Twins and The Tucker Twins.
Works by others (1921-1964) comprises the bulk of the collection. This series contains primarily proofs of comic strips, with the majority from 1948-1954. Proofs and clippings of cartoons by Fanny Y. Cory serve as examples by one of the first female cartoonists. Elmer Simms Campbell's Cuties is an example of work by one of the first African American cartoonists. The series contains numerous Blondie proofs as well as proof sheets from Dagwood Splits the Atom! that includes characters from Thimble Theater. Proofs of Donald Duck, Mickey Mouse, Snow White, Thimble Theater starring Popeye, and Popeye make up part of the series, though are partially water damaged. Also worth noting are I Love Lucy proofs from 1952-1954 created in conjunction with the television series.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized by series and arranged alphabetically by cartoon title. Materials from the same comic strip are at times not housed together because of their varying specific dimensions.
Related Material
The book Learn how Dagwood splits the atom! by Joe Musial can be located via.
Additional Pete the Tramp cartoons, Fanny Y. Cory's Little Miss Muffet, E. Simms Campbell's Cuties and Walt Disney's Merry Menagerie can be located in the
Vernon Greene Papers
.
has more than 150 collections of cartoonists' papers. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Separated Material
Hal Foster material has been transferred to the
Harold R. (Hal) Foster Papers
.
Vernon Greene material has been transferred to the
Vernon Greene Papers
.
Al Posen material has been transferred to the
Alvah Posen Papers
.
Some material was discarded due to its water damaged condition.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Art -- Illustrators; Campbell, E. Simms (Elmer Simms), 1906-1971.; Cory, Fanny Y.; Russell, C. D. (Clarence D.), 1895-1963.; Segar, E. C. (Elzie Crisler), 1894-1938.; Young, Chic, 1901-1973.; Pete the tramp (comic strip); Blondie (comic strip); American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Comic books, strips, etc. -- United States.; Cartoons (humorous images); Comic strips.; Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Unspecified, 1967.
Inventory
- Original artwork
  - Mickey Mouse by Walt Disney
    - Cartoon, Jan 29 1937; Inscribed to Gladys Clements; signed by Disney; 1 item; Possibly drawn by Floyd Gottfredson. (Map-case 1, Drawer 107)
  - Ozark Ike by Rufus "Ray" Gotto
    - Sketches, undated; comic book covers and a panel title; 4 items (Oversize 6)
  - Thimble Theatre (starring Popeye) by E.C. Segar
    - Cartoon, Aug 7 1936; Titled: "A gift horse's mouth?"; 1 item (Map-case 1, Drawer 107)
  - Miscellaneous artwork by Grover
    - Sketch, undated; 1 item (Oversize 6)
- Printed material
  - Sunday News, New York's Picture Newspaper, 1945; Jan - Oct 1946; color comic strips (Oversize 9)
    Cartoons include: Brenda Starr Reporter; Dick Tracy; The Gumps; Little Orphan Annie; Smitty; Sweeney & Son; Gasoline Alley; Tiny Tim; Terry and the Pirates; Terry; Moon Mullins; Kitty Higgins.
    1945 advertisements include: Warren's mint cocktail chewing gum; Nabisco Shredded Wheat; Maybeline; Ponds; Aunt Jemima; Cheerios; Gillette shaving cream; Pepsi-cola; Kix; Pyrex; Welch's grape juice; movie ads.
    1946 advertisements include: Little Lulu for Kleenex tissues, Ponds, Colgate, Vaseline Hair Tonic, Spam, Listerine tooth paste, Funk & Wagnall's New Standard Encyclopedia, Peter Pain in Ben-Gay ads; Pepsodent; movie ads, for example, Alfred Hitchcock’s Spellbound.
  - Sunday News, New York's Picture Newspaper, Oct - Dec 1946; 1947,; Jan - Mar 1948; color comic strips (Oversize 10)
    Cartoons similar to Oversize 9; also includes Jinglet.
    1947 advertisements include: book club membership; Schwinn-built bicycle; Prince Albert tobacco; Effanbee dolls; American Flyer Kremel dessert; Raleigh cigarettes; Captain Midnight Spy-scope; Fleer’s Dubble Bubble; Anacin; Philco Portable Phonograph; Parker Quink ink; Veto, Colgate’s new deodorant; Woodbury facial soap; Royal chocolate pudding; Satina; Freezone, liquid corn remover; movie ads, such as, Tycoon; The Secret Life of Walter Mitty.
    1948 advertisements include: Quaker Oats; Fleers Peppermint gum; Two in One shoe polish; Polident; Ford; Florida tangerines; Poligrip; movie ads, for example, Bambi.
  - Sunday News, New York's Picture Newspaper, March - Dec 1948; Jan - Jun 1949; color comic strips (Oversize 11)
    Cartoons include: Dick Tracy; Little Orphan Annie; Terry; The Gumps; Smilin' Jack; Moon Mullins; Brenda Starr Reporter; Smitty; Smokey Stover; Timmy; The Gumps; Gasoline Alley; Sweeney & Son; Little Joe; Tiny Tim; Harold Teen; Harold Teen; Ripples; Poor Little Rich Man.
    1948 advertisements include: Minit-rub, product from Bristol-Myers; Ben-gay, Colgate; Welch’s; Phillip Morris, “no cigarette hangover”; Instant Maxwell House Coffee; V-8; Camel; Gillette; Dreft; Norma Lights (Electric Corporation); Aunt Jemima; Dreft; Delrich margarine; Oxydol; Instant Postum; Danderine (dandruff relief); Lyons Toothpaste-tek and Tooth Brush (Johnson & Johnson); Fitch ideal hair tonic; Lionel trains; Old Dutch cleanser; Rice Krispes; Dash dog food; Scripto pens and pencils; Kraft dairy fresh caramels; Tootsie rolls; Wheaties; Chiffon soap flakes; Kraft malted milk; The Golden Hawk by Frank Yerby (full page book ad); Betty Crocker Crustquick, pie crust mix; Ford; Ivory Soap; movie ads, such as, Joan of Arc; A Song is Born.
    1949 advertisements include: Tide; Kellog's Rice Krispies; V-8; Little Lulu for Kleenex; Spic and Span; Ken-L-Bar dog food; Lipton tea; Peter Pan peanut butter; Little Women Jewel Box; Quaker Puffed Rice; Seven-Up; Pepsi-cola; Oxydol; Ajax; Fab cleaner, Rinso; Post Toasties; Glo-coat; Camel (T zone ads: T for Taste and T for throat); Phillip Morris; Roy Rogers toy prize; Nestle semi-sweet chocolate; sweet milk cocoa; Maxwell House Coffee; Corn Flakes; Aunt Jemima.
  - Sunday News, New York's Picture Newspaper, Old Glory issue, 4 Jul 1948; color (Oversize 16)
    Features article on "White House Dresses from 1789 to 1945."
  - Miscellaneous, 1949; undated; 6 items (Oversize 5)
    Documents from the New York Historical Society found with Dick's Adventures in Dreamland; includes a letter from the National Park Service; plans for City Hall Park in New York.
- Works by C.D. Russell
  All comics by Russell feature Pete the Tramp.
  - Bumps, Jan - Jun 1932; color proofs (Oversize 1)
  - Pete's Pup, Jun - Dec 1932; Jan - Jul 1933,; 1934,; Jan - Feb 1935; color proofs (Oversize 1)
  - Pete the Tramp, 1943; 1946-1947,; 1951; color clippings (Oversize 15)
  - Pete the Tramp, 1936-1947; color proofs (Oversize 12)
    Includes horizontal and vertical cartoon layouts. One 1944 proof contains Lyman Young's Curley Harper. 1943, 1946-47 contain some newspaper clippings.
  - Pete the Tramp, 1948-1959; color proofs (Oversize 13)
    Includes horizontal and vertical cartoon layouts. 1951 includes some newspaper clippings. 1957 includes mostly black and white proofs; 1958-63 contain only black and white proofs.
  - Pete the Tramp, 1960-1963; black and white proofs (Oversize 14)
  - Snorky, 1935-1940; color proofs (Oversize 2)
    1940 includes 3 items.
  - The Topper Twins, Apr - Jun 1935; color proofs (Oversize 2)
  - The Tucker Twins, Mar - Apr 1935; color proofs (Oversize 2)
- Works by others
  - Barney Google and Snuffy Smith by Fred Lasswell
    - Proof, Oct 1954; 1 item (Oversize 16)
  - Beetle Bailey by Mort Walker
    - Proof, Oct 1954; 1 item (Oversize  7)
  - Big Ben Bolt by John Cullen Murphy
    - Clippings, 1952; 1954; 4 items (Oversize 16)
      Three items in color; 1952 clippings include Rip Kirby and Buz Sawyer.
    - Proof, Oct 1954; 1 item (Oversize 16)
    - Proofs, 1951-1952; 1954,; 1956; 3 folders (Oversize 4)
      One color proof; bulk of dates from 1951.
  - Big Sister by Bob Naylor
    - Clipping, Oct 1954; 1 item (Oversize 16)
  - Blondie by Chic Young
    - Clippings, 1934-1939; 1951,; 1953; color; 5 folders (Oversize  8)
      Include Colonel Potterby and the Duchess; Roy Rogers; Flash Gordon; The Lone Ranger and more.
    - Proofs, 1935-1936; 1954-1955; 4 folders (Oversize  6)
      One color proof; some include Colonel Potterby and the Duchess.
    - Proofs, 1946; 1948,; 1954; 7 items (Oversize 16)
    - Proofs, 1951-1952; 1953-1954; 4 folders (Oversize 6)
      Some include Colonel Potterby and the Duchess.
  - The Breaking Point by Bud Blake
    - Proof, 1954; 1 item (Oversize 7)
      Also includes panels of: Office Hours; Oh, Happy Day!; Public Enemy; Home, Sweet Home; Growing Pains.
  - Brick Bradford by Clarence Gray
    - Proof, 1954; color proof; 1 item (Oversize 14)
  - Brick Bradford by Paul Norris
    - Proof, Oct 1954; 1 item (Oversize 16)
  - Buz Sawyer by Roy Crane
    - Proofs, 1946; 1954; 2 items (Oversize 7)
  - Buz Sawyer featuring His Pal Roscoe Sweeney by Roy Crane
    - Proofs, 1952-1953; 1956; black and white; 2 folders (Oversize 14)
      Bulk of dates from 1952.
  - "Cap" Stubbs and Tippie by Edwina (Dumm)
    See also Tippie.
    - Proofs, undated; 17 items (Oversize 4)
  - The Cisco Kid by Jose Luis Salinas
    - Proof, Oct 1954; 1 item (Oversize 16)
  - Colonel Potterby and the Duchess by Chic Young
    See also Blondie.
    - Clippings, 1935-1937; color; 18 items (Oversize 16)
    - Proofs, 1936; 1947-1949; black and white; 2 folders (Oversize 3)
  - Cuties by E. Simms Campbell
    - Proof, Oct 1954; 1 item (Oversize  7)
  - Dagwood Splits the Atom! by Chic Young and Joe Musial
    - Proofs, 1948; 4 items (Oversize  6)
      See Blondie and Related Material.
  - Dick's Adventures in Dreamland by Neil O'Keeffe and Max Trell
    - Clipping, 26 Aug 1951; 1 item (Oversize 8)
      Includes Rusty Riley.
    - Proofs, 1947-1949; 1950,; 1951,; 1953; Three color proofs.; 3 folders (Oversize 1)
  - Double Trouble by Bill MacLean
    - Proofs, 1949; 1 folder (Oversize  6)
  - Dumb Dora by Paul Fung
    - Clippings, 1931; 1932; color; 4 items (Oversize  7)
  - Elmer by Doc Winner
    - Proof, 09 Sep 1954; color proof; 1 item (Oversize 14)
  - El Raton Miguelito (Mickey Mouse) by Walt Disney
    See also Mickey Mouse.
    - Proof, 01 Aug 1936; in Spanish; 1 item (Oversize 3)
  - Etta Kett by Paul Robinson
    - Proofs, 1948; 1954; 2 items (Oversize 7)
    - Proofs, 1954; 1956; 2 items (Oversize 14)
      One color proof.
  - Fatso by Clyde Lewis
    - Proofs, 1949; 1 folder (Oversize 6)
  - Flash Gordon by Mac Raboy and Don Moore
    - Clippings, 1951-1952; color; 2 items (Oversize 16)
    - Proofs, 1950; 1954,; 1957; 3 items (Oversize  6)
  - Flash Gordon by Dan Barry
    - Proofs, 1954; black and white; 2 items (Oversize 16)
  - The Flop Family by George "Swan" Swanson
    - Proofs, 1948; Oct 1954; 1 folder (Oversize 16)
    - Proofs, 1949; 1 folder (Oversize 6)
  - Gags and Gals by Jefferson Machamer
    - Clippings, 1935-1936; color; 2 folders (Oversize 16)
      From the Sunday Mirror Comic Section. Includes Toonerville Folks; Little Stanley.
    - Clippings, 1937-1938; color; 12 items (Oversize 8)
      Bulk from 1937; Includes It's Papa Who Pays!; Bubbling Bill; Simple Sylvia.
  - Gasoline Alley by Frank O. King
    - Proof, 1921; 1 item (Oversize 4)
      No signature.
  - Glamor Girls by Don Flowers
    - Proof, Oct 1954; 1 item (Oversize 16)
  - Grandma by Charles "Chas." Kuhn
    - Proofs, 1949-1950; 2 folders (Oversize 14)
      Includes both horizontal and vertical proof sheets and one panel title.
    - Proof, Oct 1954; 1 item (Oversize 8)
  - The Heart of Juliet Jones by Stan Drake
    - Clippings, Oct 1954; 2 items (Oversize 8)
    - Proofs, 1954; 1956; 3 items (Oversize 5)
      Two color proofs.
  - Henry by Carl Anderson
    - Proofs, Jul - Oct 1949; 1 folder (Oversize 14)
      Both horizontal and vertical proof sheets.
    - Proofs, 1949; Oct 1954; 2 items (Oversize 16)
  - Hi and Louis by Dik Browne
    - Proof, Oct 1954; 1 item; Comic originally created by Browne and Mort Walker. (Oversize 16)
  - Hopalong Cassidy by Dan Spiegle
    - Proof, Oct 1954; 1 item (Oversize 7)
  - Hubert by Dick Wingert
    - Proofs, 1948-1949; black and white; 1 folder (Oversize 4)
    - Proofs, 1948; 1954; 2 items (Oversize  7)
  - I Love Lucy by Bob Lawrence
    - Proofs, Dec 1952; 1953; 1 folder (Oversize 6)
      Bulk from 1953.
    - Proof, Oct 1954; 1 item (Oversize 16)
  - Johnny Hazard by Frank Robbins
    - Clippings, 1948; 1954; 2 items (Oversize 15)
    - Proofs, 1950; 2 items (Oversize 6)
  - Jon Jason by Elmer Wexler
    - Proofs, 1946; 1 folder (Oversize 6)
      The Chicago Sun Syndicate.
  - Joseph the Provider by Thomas Mann and C. B. Falls
    - Clippings, 1944 (Oversize 8)
      Part of Book-of-the-Month Club; King Features Syndicate.
  - Jungle Jim by Paul Norris and Don Moore
    - Proofs, 1950-1952; black and white; 1 folder (Oversize 14)
  - The Katzenjammer Kids by Harold Knerr
    - Proofs, 1949; black and white; 4 items (Oversize 3)
      Includes Dinglehoofer Und His Dog.
  - The King's General by George Tetzel
    - Proofs, undated (Oversize 8)
      Based on the novel by Daphne Du Maurier; part of Book-of-the-Month Club; King Features Syndicate.
  - King of the Royal Mounted by Zane Grey
    - Clippings, 1936; Sep 9 1937; 3 items (Oversize 15)
      See Texas Thorne. Includes Colonel Potterby and the Duchess; Room and Board.
  - Little Annie Rooney by Brandon Walsh and Nicholas Afonsky
    - Clippings, 1936-1937; color; 2 folders (Oversize 8)
      Includes Heroes of American History; Curley Harper; The Squirrel Cage; Room and Board; Tim Tyler's Luck; Colonel Potterby and the Duchess; King of the Royal Mounted.
  - Little Annie Rooney by Brandon Walsh and Darrell McClure
    - Proofs, 1949; 1 folder (Oversize 14)
    - Proof, Oct 1954; 1 item (Oversize 15)
  - Little Iodine by Jimmy Hatlo
    - Proofs, 1949; black and white; 1 folder (Oversize 14)
  - Little Miss Muffet by Fanny Y. Cory
    - Proof, Oct 1954; 1 item (Oversize 15)
  - Little Sport by John Henry Rouson
    - Proof, circa 1954; color; 1 item (Oversize  5)
  - The Little Woman by Don Tobin
    - Proof, Nov 1953; 1 item (Oversize 14)
    - Proofs, Oct 1954; 2 items (Oversize 8)
  - The Lone Ranger by Charles Flanders
    - Proof, Oct 1954; 1 item (Oversize 15)
  - Mandrake the Magician by Lee Falk and Phil Davis
    - Proof, 1954; color; 1 item (Oversize 5)
  - Mickey Mouse by Walt Disney
    See also El Raton Miguelito.
    - Clippings, 1935; color; 7 items (Oversize 15)
      Includes an article about the color screen debut of Mickey Mouse; topper Silly Symphony.
    - Proofs, 1935-1936; 1938; black and white; 1 folder (Oversize 3)
    - Proofs, 1936-1938; black and white; 1 folder (Oversize 3)
      Topper cartoons include Donald Duck; Silly Symphony; Snow White.
    - Proofs, 1954; black and white; 4 items (Oversize 7)
      Includes Donald Duck; two Merry Menagerie.
  - Mister Breger by Dave Breger
    - Proof, Oct 1954; 1 item (Oversize 8)
      Includes Fanny Y. Cory's Sonny Sayings.
  - Muggs McGinnis by Wally Bishop
    - Proofs, 1933-1934; 2 items; Retitled Muggs and Skeeter in 1936. (Oversize  7)
  - Muggs and Skeeter by Wally Bishop
    - Proofs, 1948-1949; 1954; 1 folder (Oversize 7)
  - Myrtle by Dudley Fisher
    - Proofs, 1949; 1 folder (Oversize  5)
  - Ozark Ike by Rufus"Ray" Gotto
    - Proofs, 1947-1950; 5 folders (Oversize 4)
      Horizontal and vertical proofs. 1947 includes color proofs of Ozark Ike's Whodunits; 1950 contains panel titles and panel title negatives.
  - Ozark Ike by Bill Lignante
    - Proof, 1954; 1 item (Oversize 8)
  - Perry Mason in the "Case of the Missing Husband" by Erle Stanley Gardner
    - Proof, Mar-Apr 1951; 1 item (Oversize 14)
  - The Phantom by Wilson McCoy
    - Proof, 1954; 1 item (Oversize 8)
  - Polly and Her Pals by Cliff Sterrett
    - Proofs, 1948-1950; 1952,; 1954,; 1956-1957; 1 folder (Oversize 14)
      One color proof from 1954. Bulk of proofs from 1949.
  - Popeye (in Thimble Theatre) by Tom Sims and Bill Zaboly
    - Proofs, Jun-Oct 1951; 21 items (Oversize 6)
  - Professor Phumble by Bill Yates
    - Proofs, 1960; 1961; 2 folders (Oversize 5)
  - Private Life of Buck by Cylde Lewis
    - Proof, 1948; 1 item (Oversize 15)
  - Red Barry by Will Gould
    - Clippings, 1936-1937; 2 folders (Oversize 15)
    - Clippings, 1936-1937; 5 items (Oversize 7)
      Includes Radio Patrol; The Little Woman; Way Out West; Dinglehoofer Und His Dog; The Katzenjammer Kids; The Squirrel Cage.
  - Rick O'Shay by Stan Lynde
    - Proof, Jan 12 1964; color; 1 item (Oversize 14)
  - Right Around Home by Dudley Fisher
    - Proofs, 1949; Sep 26 1954; 1 folder (Oversize 14)
  - Ripley's Believe It or Not
    - Proof, 26 Sep 1954; color; 1 item (Oversize 3)
      Includes Bringing Up Father and They'll Do It Every Time.
      Possibly drawn by Paul Frehm.
  - Rip Kirby by Alex Raymond
    - Proofs, Jul 1948; Oct 1954; 2 items (Oversize 8)
    - Proofs, 1951-1953; 1954-1956; 2 folders (Oversize 4)
  - Room and Board by Gene Ahern
    - Proofs, Jul - Oct 1949 (Oversize 14)
    - Proofs, Oct 1954; 2 items (Oversize 7)
  - Roy Rogers, King of the Cowboys by Al McKimson
    - Proof, 1950; 1 item (Oversize 5)
    - Proof, Oct 1954; 1 item (Oversize 15)
  - Rusty Riley by Frank Godwin
    - Proofs, Aug-Sep 1948; 1954 (Oversize 7)
      Bulk of dates from 1948.
    - Proof, 19 Sep 1948; black and white; 1 item (Oversize 5)
  - Sam's Strip by Mort Walker and Jerry Dumas
    - Proofs, 1961-1962; black and white; 2 folders (Oversize 5)
  - Secret Agent X9 by Mel Graff
    - Clippings, 1946; 1948,; 2 items (Oversize 7)
      Strip originally created by Dashiell Hammett and Alex Raymond.
    - Proof, 1950; 1 item (Oversize 5)
  - Silly Symphony (featuring Donald Duck) by Walt Disney
    - Proof, 27 Dec 1936; 1 item (Oversize 5)
  - Skull Valley by Garrett Price
    - Clippings, 1936; 5 items (Oversize 15)
      Includes Gasoline Alley; Herby; Smitty.
  - Smokey Stover by Bill Holman
    - Clipping, 1938; color; 1 item (Oversize 15)
      Includes Spooky. Advertisements: Butterfinger and Pepsodent.
  - Smythes by Rea Irvin
    - Clippings, 1936; color; 1 folder (Oversize 8)
  - The Story of Martha Wayne by Wilson Scruggs
    - Cartoon Booklet, 1953 (Oversize 5)
  - Strictly Richter by Mischa Richter
    - Proofs, 1948; 1954 (Oversize 7)
      Includes Jellybean Jones.
  - Sunflower Street by Tom Little
    See the
    Vernon Greene Papers
    .
    - Proof, Aug 1948; 1 item (Oversize 15)
  - Susie Q. Smith by Linda and Jerry Walter
    - Proofs, 1949; 1 folder (Oversize 5)
  - Texas Thorne by Zane Grey
    - Clippings, 1936; 1937; 2 folders (Oversize 7)
      Includes King of the Royal Mounted; Little Annie Rooney; Room and Board; Curley Harper; Radio Patrol; The Squirrel Cage.
  - They'll Do It Every Time by Jimmy Hatlo
    - Proofs, Oct 1954; 17 Jun 1961; 3 items (Oversize 7)
      Includes one color clipping.
  - Thimble Theatre (starring Popeye) by E.C. Segar
    - Clippings, 1935-1938; color; 2 folders (Oversize 15)
      Bulk from 1936-1937; from comic pictorials like New York Evening Journal and Journal American. Includes Buck Rogers.
    - Clippings, 1936; black and white; 1 folder (Oversize 7)
      From New York Evening Journal. Includes Pete the Tramp; Polly and her Pals; Little Annie Rooney; Blondie; Just Kids and more.
    - Proofs, 1936; 1937; 19 items (Oversize 6)
      Bulk from 1936.
  - Tillie the Toiler by Russ Westover
    - Proofs, 1949; 1 folder (Oversize 5)
      Includes horizontal and vertical proof sheets.
  - Tillie the Toiler by Bob Gustafson
    - Proofs, Oct 1954; 2 items (Oversize 7)
  - Tim Tyler's Luck by Lyman and Bob Young
    - Proof, 1954; 1 item (Oversize 7)
  - Tippie by Edwina (Dumm)
    See also "Cap" Stubbs and Tippie.
    - Proofs, undated; 1 folder (Oversize 5)
  - Tommy of the Big Top by John Lehti
    - Proof, Jul 1948; 1 item (Oversize 7)
  - Tuffy by Syd Hoff
    - Proofs, 1949; 1 folder (Oversize 5)